Prashanth Iyer

Contact Information E-mail: munichlinux@gmail.com

 $Current\ Location:\ {\bf Sunnyvale,\ US.}$

Mobile: +1(415) 622-5201.

Bio

Currently, Sr.Software Engineer at Argo. 10+ years of software engineering experience. A passionate programmer who loves design pattern, functional programming and enjoys Himalayan hikes.

Git: http://github.com/ipiyer

Skills

• Languages: NodeJS, Python.

• Data Pipeline: Kafka, Spark, Airflow.

• Database: PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcache, MySQL, CouchDB.

Frameworks: Django, Express.DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes.

• Web: HTML, CSS, WebSockets, React.

Employment

ArgoAi, Sr.Software Engineer

(October 2019 - Current)

Part of the maps team; my role is to build tools for map production.

- Created an interface for building Base Map and Vector Map.
- Implemented a system for map publishing.
- Built metasearch for the drivable area.

Novelet. Founder

(April 2019 - September 2019)

Novelet is an Audio/Visual of a digital book.

Built the following:

- A distributed book processor.
- Processing pipeline with NLP, TTS, Summary, Entity recognition.
- React audio player, text highlighter, book reader.
- The Infrastructure is built on GCP and Kubernetes.

Roku Inc., Sr. Software Engineer

(October 2017 - March 2019)

Part of voice service/AI team; my role is to build the voice service infrastructure and data pipeline.

- Implemented VAD for far-field devices(WebRTC based).
- Built an application level metrics with auto failover for external services.
- Designed a device state retrieval system with Go, Kafka, Redis, and Apache Spark.
- Wrote an ETL data pipeline for machine learning with Spark and Airflow.
- Built an offline data analysis to detect NLP error rates.

Search, Yahoo Inc., Software Dev Eng, Sr.

(December 2015 - September 2017)

Built the backend to syndicate search data to partner network.

- Scaled the API to 4000 QPS.
- Built a fraud detection system that prevented keywords abuse and improved revenue.
- Redesigned the system to use docker container, which can scale based on the traffic.

Mobius Justice, co-founder

(June 2016 - April 2017)

Mobius is an Outcomes Driven Platform that provides the department of probation with insights into the performance of their client population (google analytics for juvenile probation system).

- The platform was built on Gitlab, GCP, Kubernetes, Docker, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, and React.
- Built unit testing framework for database queries, a system that can generate sample dataset, create a sandbox environment, and test SQL.
- Wrote a framework to write SQL with Function composition.

YSB, Yahoo Inc., Software Dev Eng, Sr.

(November 2013 - November 2015)

- Rewrote the legacy stack with NodeJS, made the application device friendly.
- Built A/B testing infrastructure, analytics platform, and continuous deployment.
- Reduced development cycle from weeks to hours.
- Rebuilt the payments system with Zuora.

Flickr, Yahoo Inc., Lead Engineer, San Francisco, CA. (April 2013 - October 2013)

Web Hosting, Yahoo Inc., Lead Engineer, India

(July 2010 - March 2013)

- Re-architected the old PHP stack to NodeJS.
- Build Template testing framework which reduced the testing cost by one-third.
- Introduced Frontend best practices, TDD and BDD.

Sportxiom Ventures, Web Architect, India

2009 - 2010

I was responsible for building a real-time sports application in Python, Django, and JavaScript.

Info Edge, Senior Software Engineer, India

2008 - 2009

Cleartrip, Graduate Engineer, India

2007 - 2008

Cleartrip is an online travel company providing online booking services for flights and train tickets. I was part of the air search team; I learned Lisp, Web Development, and Functional Programming.

Education

B.Tech Information Technology, Anna University, India.

(June 2003 - Nov 2007)